Teachers Union of the City of New York Records 5015
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Legislation, salary campaign, grassroots, 1954-1955 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  Fact sheet, bulletins, press release, correspondence form letters, sign-up sheets, salary newsletters, reprint
- Legislation, salary campaign, grass roots movement, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  Post cards, telegrams, resolutions, memos, bulletins statements, news clippings, newsletters, correspondence form letters
- Legislation, salary campaign, Meyer salary fact-finding committee hearings, 1950-1951 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  Bulletins, briefs, reports, graph, press releases, salary schedule, memos, petitions, summaries, case, statements, news clippings
- Legislation, salary campaign, mimeographed, printed material, 1950-1951 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  News clippings, post cards, bulletins, statements, press releases, resolutions, telegrams, petitions, form letters, pamphlet
- Legislation, salary campaign, miscellaneous clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 69, Folder 2)
- Legislation, salary campaign, Moore Committee Report, 1951 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  Press releases, salary schedules, news clippings, committee member list
- Legislation, salary campaign, out-of-town salaries, 1953-1954 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, news clippings, pamphlet, salary schedules, routing slip
- Legislation, salary campaign, salary schedules, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  Salary schedules
- Legislation, salary campaign, single salary schedule, 1954 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, comparison, statement, news clippings
- Legislation, salary campaign, statements and reports (other than T.U. ), 1947-1951 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  Bulletins, pamphlet
- Legislation, salary campaign, stoppage of extracurricular activity, P.T.A. action, 1950 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, bulletin, telegram
- Legislation, salary campaign, T.U. printed material, 1949-1950 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  Bulletins, form letters, leaflets, resolutions, memo, petition form, post cards
- Legislation, school budget briefs and programs, 1950-1952 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  Briefs, statements, outlines
- Legislation, substitutes, social security, 1953-1954 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  Telegram, memos, press releases, resolution, acts, report, bulletins, news clippings, correspondence, form letters
- Legislation, substitutes, social security, 1954-1955 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  Bulletins, memos, telegram, correspondence, news clippings
- Legislative Index Company, 1955-1962 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  Memo, correspondence, form letters, subscription forms
- In re: case of J. Lemansky, 1952 (Box 70, Folder 1)
- Reports of cases before Arthur Levitt, Committee of the Board of Education, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  Summations
- Librarians Committee, 1947-1953 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, form letter, comparison of require; Local 5 See: American Federation of Teachers, Local 5 Local 555 See: Teachers Union File See: Teachers Union Local 555 Loyalty Oaths See: Academic Freedom McCarran Committee See: Congressional Investigations
- McCarran Committee, 1952 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, bill, news clippings, notes, editorial
- McCarthy, Joseph, censure resolution, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  News clipping, correspondence, statement
- In re: Case of V. Jerauld McGill, Louis Weisner, Charles Hughes, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  Briefs, report
- Membership Meetings Minutes, 1940-1964 (Box 70, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous, 1936-1965 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  Bulletins, leaflets, brief, questionnaire, form letters, publications, correspondence, memorandums of understanding, senate bill; Mundt-Nixon-Ferguson Bill See: Legislation
- Music teachers, 1951-1955 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, form letters, invitations, bulletins, report
- Music teachers committee, 1948-1950 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletins
- New York City, Mayor's Office, 1955-1956 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  News clippings, post cards, press releases, petition form, bulletin, correspondence
- New York State Joint Legislative Committee. Investigation on Public Educational System, 1941 (Box 71a, Folder 1)
  Hearings, ( 4 bound volumes)
- New York State Labor Department, 1947-1956 (Box 71a, Folder 2)
- New York City Public School Budget, 1921-1935 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, form letters, press releases
- New York election campaign, 1954 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  Questionnaire, press releases, poll, news clippings, correspondence, form letters, sample resolution, statement
- New York State Teachers Association, 1950-1963 (Box 71a, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, news clippings; Newark Cases See: Academic Freedom
- New York election campaign, N.Y. Teachers News, 1954 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  News clippings, correspondence, form letters
- New York Peace Institute, 1952 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, address, program
- New York State Department of Education (General), 1954-1960 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, form letters, study, news clippings, report, statement, regents proposals, list of publications
- New York State Department of Education, Dr. James E. Allen, Jr., Commissioner, 1953-1960 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, telegram, news clippings
- New York State Department of Education, Dr. Charles A. Brind, Jr., Counsel, 1952-1960 (Box 71, Folder 8)
- New York State Governor's Office, 1954-1956 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, press releases, copy of telegram, post cards
- In re: Case of Arthur Newman, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  Case; Organized Union Majority See: American Federation of Teachers, Local 5
- Organizing, 1948-1962 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletins, questionnaires pamphlets, post cards, news clippings
- Organizing Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, pamphlets
- Parents Association, United, 1934-1936 (Box 72, Folder 4)
- Pension, 1950-1960 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, form letters, receipt, copyright, statements, news clippings, summaries, revisions, brief, congressional record, case, memo, fact sheet, petition form, press releases
- Pension Credit, Garvin Shevron Suit, 1959-1960 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  News clippings, petitions
- Pension Credit for Substitute Service, Paul Becker Case, 1959-1960 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, brief, news clippings
- Pension Election, 1952-1953 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, form letters, poster, news clipping
- Pension Suit, Ella Jackson, annuity-disability retirement, 1959-1960 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  Cases, news clippings, correspondence, petition
- Pensions, cases, 1952-1953 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  Statement, correspondence, briefs, memos, press releases, news clipping, papers on appeal
- Press Relations, Amsterdam News, 1953-1957 (Box 72, Folder 11)
- Press Relations, The Churchman, 1953-1954 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, receipts
- Press Relations, The Daily Compass, 1949-1950 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  Telegrams, correspondence
- Press Relations, I.F. Stone's Weekly, 1953-1954 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, reprints
- Press Relations, Manchester Guardian, 1955-1956 (Box 73, Folder 4)
- Press Relations, March of Labor, 1951-1954 (Box 73, Folder 5)
- Press Relations, The Nation, 1952-1961 (Box 73, Folder 6)
- Press Relations, National Guardian, 1953-1960 (Box 73, Folder 7)
- Press Relations, New York Herald Tribune, 1947-1961 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, telegrams, photocopy, reprint
- Press Relations, New York Journal American, 1948-1951 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, reprints, telegram
- Press Relations, New York Post, 1948-1961 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  Reprints, correspondence, telegrams, form letters, news clippings, bulletins
- Press Relations, New York Times, 1949-1962 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, news clippings, telegrams, press release
- Press Relations, New York World Telegram and Sun, 1947-1962 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  Correspondence, news clipping, press releases, memos, telegrams, correspondence, contracts
- Press Releases, 1958-1959 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  Press releases, notes, statement
- Private School Section of T.U., 1928-1951 (Box 73, Folder 14)
  Pamphlets, program, form letters, minutes, reports, bulletins, proposed contracts
- Private Schools, 1956-1960 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletins, invitation news clipping, contracts, questionnaire; Progressive Education Association See: Academic Freedom, Committee, Progressive Education Association
- Rank and File, struggle, 1933-1935 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  Resolution, statement, news bulletin, pamphlet, bulletins, correspondence, form letters
- Rebuilding Union after split, 1935-1936 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  Summary, releases, statements, bulletins, reports, leaflets, correspondence, form letters
- Referenda, 1941 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  Regulations, statements, ballots, bulletins, pamphlets, news clippings, publication, correspondence form letters, receipt, speech
- Reports, 1932-1935 (Box 74, Folder 4a)
  Printed reports of Special Grievance Committee
- Retirement and Social Security, 1956-1957 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, social security, benefits, comparison, summary, statements, acts
- Rose Russell, 1957-1962 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, pamphlet, news clipping, publication; Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt
- Rose Russell, 1949-1955 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, autobiographical sketch, memo, bulletin
- Rose Russell, speeches, 1951-1962 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  Speeches
- Rose Russell, tribute, 1963-1964 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  Reservations, tickets, correspondence, programs, telegrams, list, speech, news clippings, guest lists
- Salary Differential, Elaine Berlin Case, 1960-1961 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  News clippings, correspondence, cases
- School clerks, 1952-1953 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  Form letters, correspondence, statement, bulletins
- School conditions (miscellaneous), 1957-1962 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  Memo, correspondence, news clippings
- School Conditions, administration, 1960-1962 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  Nevs clippings, correspondence
- School Conditions, age of school "buildings", 1951 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  Report, chart
- School Conditions, class size, 1949-1955 (Box 75, Folder 6)
  Memos, questionnaires, circulars, statement, nevs clippings, pamphlets, correspondence, form letters
- School Conditions, class size, 1955-1961 (Box 75, Folder 7)
  Form letter, correspondence, press release, nevs clippings
- School Conditions, class size and overcrowding, 1961-1963 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, form letters, news clippings, press release, brief, recommendations
- School Conditions, clippings, photos, 1952-1954 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  Form letter, news clippings, photographs
- School Conditions, educational program, 1958-1962 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  Press release, form letter, questionnaire, publication
- School Conditions, enrollment, 1962 (Box 75, Folder 11)
- School Conditions, financing, 1958-1960 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  News clippings, pamphlet, expenditure, -listing, study
- School Conditions, grievances, 1956-1962 (Box 75, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, form letters, supplement, pamphlet, telegram, news clippings
- School Conditions, higher education, 1961-1962 (Box 75, Folder 14)
- School Conditions, length of school, 1950-1960 (Box 75, Folder 15)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletin, news clippings
- School Conditions, miscellaneous, 1948-1951 (Box 75, Folder 16)
  Program, release, report, pamphlet
- School Conditions, narcotics, 1951-1954 (Box 75, Folder 17)
  Resolution, press releases, news clippings, reports, publication, correspondence
- School Conditions, overcrowding, 1954-1960 (Box 75, Folder 18)
  Correspondence, release, news clipping
- School Conditions, retardation, 1949-1957 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  Publications, recommendation, releases, correspondence, form letters, reports, news clippings
- School Conditions, Schinnerer Report, 1961-1962 (Box 76, Folder 2)
  Reports, correspondence, news clippings
- School Conditions, school construction, 1949-1954 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  Statements, analysis and recommendations, form letters
- School Conditions, school construction, 1951-1958 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, leaflet, form letters, release, preamble, report
- School Conditions, school lunches and aides, 1962 (Box 76, Folder 5)
- School Conditions, teachers shortage, 1950-1956 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  Analysis, addendum, estimate, proposals, correspondence, publication
- School Conditions, teachers shortage, 1961-1963 (Box 76, Folder 7)
  News clippings, memo
- School Conditions, Teacher shortage, science and math teachers, 1956-1957 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, questionnaires, status information, news release, resolutions, news clippings
- School Conditions, vocational schools, 1941-1943 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  Brief, news releases, correspondence, form letters
- School Conditions, vocational high schools, 1950-1963 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, form letters, questionnaire, summary, memo, news clippings, bulletin
- School Conditions, vocational high school committee, 1951-1959 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, form letters, circular, news clipping, bulletins, resolution, statements, press release, questionnaire
- School Relief Fund, 1931-1933 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, clippings, form letters
- School Relief Fund, 1932-1933 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  Press releases, memo, correspondence, notes, reports
- Schools, summer activities, 1951-1954 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  Press releases, form letters, correspondence, news clippings, bulletin
- Schools, vocational, 1950-1951 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, form letters, news release, bulletins. post cards, memo, tentative plan, brief, petition
- Scrapbooks, 1917-1918 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  Scrapbooks (9 volumes)
- In re: Case of Morris J. Skovion, 1953 (Box 77, Folder 8)
- Social Security, 1958-1962 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, an act, news clipping, photocopy
- Social Security, correspondence, inquiries, 1955-1960 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, form letters, acts, news clippings, press release, comparative study
- Social Security, correspondence and miscellaneous, 1961-1962 (Box 78, Folder 2)
- Social Security, referendum and miscellaneous, 1955-1960 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, notes, leaflet, pamphlet, memo, bulletins, news clippings
- Songs, 1952-1956 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  Songs
- Lucile Spence, June 9th Party, 1961 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, telegrams, news clipping
- In re: Case of Isaac Sperber, 1954 (Box 78, Folder 6)
- In re: Case of Isaac Sperber, 1955 (Box 78, Folder 7)
- Abraham Squire et al, Board of Education, cases, Report of Arthur Levitt, Trial Examiner, 1953-1955 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  Cases, appeals, legal papers, receipt, correspondence memos
- State Federation of Teachers, 1941-1942 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, minutes, note
- Strikes, 1960-1963 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  News clippings, press releases, statements, telegram bulletins, correspondence, form letters
- Substitutes Bulletin, 1950-1956 (Box 79, Folder 2)
- Substitute Committee, 1947-1956 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  Lesson plans for subs, petition forms, memo, bullet: notes, resolutions, telegrams, receipt, briefs, report, circular, press releases, correspondence, form letters, questionnaires
- Substitute Teachers, 1948-1949 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  Form letters, correspondence, telegram, Bill of Rights, memo, press releases, petition forms, statements, recommendations, suggestions, resolutions, bulletins
- Substitute Teachers, 1950-1953 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletins, news clippings, statements, petition forms, eligibility requirements, resolutions, press releases, lesson plans, telegrams, cases, appeals, post cards, announcements
- Substitute Teachers, miscellaneous (Box 79, Folder 6)
  Suggestions for letter, bulletin, blank forms, Bill of Rights, post cards, leaflet, resolution, form letters; Supreme Court Justices, correspondence See: Academic Freedom. No date.
- Supreme Court of U.S.A., case of Morris U. Schappes against people of State of New York, 1943 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  Briefs, petition; Suspension of Eight See: Academic Freedom
- Teachers Alliance, 1956-1959 (Box 79, Folder 7a)
  Correspondence, bulletin, leaflets; Teachers Hearings See: Academic Freedom
- Teachers Grievances, 1923-1935 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, releases, brief, synopsis of eligibility requirements
- Teachers Interest Committee (TIC), 1954-1961 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  Telegram, resolutions, press releases, bulletins, correspondence, form letters, news clipping
- Teachers Retirement Board, 1955-1963 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  Publications, bulletin, correspondence, resolution, news clippings
- Teachers Salary, pamphlets, 1947-1951 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  Pamphlets, bulletin
- Teachers Strikes, 1951-1959 (Box 80, Folder 3)
- Teacher Training, 1955-1961 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  Teacher preparation paper, primers
- Teacher Unemployment, 1930-1939 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  Memo, press releases, notice, summary, correspondence
- Teachers Union, 1916-1964 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  History, reprints
- Teachers Union Agreement, 1951 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  Agreement (pamphlet)
- Teachers Union, dissolution and correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  Correspondence, form letters, resolution
- Teachers Union, Education Department, 1950-1951 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  Order blanks, post card, High-Lights sheet, bulletins, form letter
- Teachers Union File, re: Irvin Adler, Arthur Aaron, 1951-1952 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, appeals, interviews, notes
- Teachers Union File, re: Irvin Adler, 1951-1952 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  News clippings, correspondence, appeals, press releases, case, post cards, findings of fact, publication, pamphlets, leaflets, applications for principal
- Teachers Union File, re: Irvin Adler et al, 1953 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  Petitioners memo, case, correspondence, receipt, post card
- Teachers Union File, case of Adler, Irvin and Wilson, etc. et al, 1953 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  Report, memo, case, news clippings, receipt, legal papers
- Teachers Union File, re: Dorothy Albert, 1952 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  News clipping, correspondence, brief, journal, appeals
- Re: File of Teachers Union, Austin et al vs. Board of Education, 1956-1959 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, memo, briefs, reply briefs, notes, appeals, news clippings
- Teachers Union File, re: Leo Auerback et al, 1953 (Box 81, Folder 4)
  Opinions, correspondence, cases, appeals, notices of Pleading
- Teachers Union File, re: Louis Belin et al, 1948-1952 (Box 81, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, case, post cards, subpoena, appeal, reports
- Teachers Union File, re: Dorothy Black and Hyman Koppelman, 1951-1953 (Box 81, Folder 6)
  Cases, correspondence, interview, exception to report
- Teachers Union File, Board of Education, Blau et al vs. Board of Education, 1956-1958 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, cases, brief, appeals
- Teachers Union File, Cases of eight teachers, 1952-1953 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  Case, argument and summation of council, report, exception to report
- Teachers Union File, re: Stella Eliashaw et al, 1953 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  Case, hearing, correspondence
- Teachers Union File, exhibit file, re: Feinberg Law, 1948-1949 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  Multicopy form letters, correspondence, clippings, court documents, press releases, mimeo, report, pamphlets
- Teachers Union File, Mildred Flacks, 1951-1952 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  Case, legal papers, correspondence
- Teachers Union File, David L. Friedman, 1950-1951 (Box 83, Folder 2)
- Teachers Union File, re: Goldway, Alexander, 1948-1953 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  Research memos, news clippings, respondents memo, petitioners reply memo, correspondence, report, notes, case, papers on appeal
- Teachers Union File, Cyril Graze, 1951-1952 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, hearing, case, form letters, press releases, legal papers
- Teachers Union File, re: Mildred Grossman et al, 1953-1954 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, case, notice of pleading, new file memo
- Teachers Union File, re: Philip Horowitz, 1952 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  Post card, appeals, correspondence
- Teachers Union File, re: Hyman Koppelman, 1951-1952 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  Telegram, correspondence, case, transcripts of hearings
- Teachers Union File, re: Abraham Lederman et al, 1950-1952 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  Notices of application, correspondence, affidavit of service, note, comment, petition
- Feinberg Law - Exhibit File (Box 83, Folder 9)
- Teachers Union File, Julius Lemansky, 1951-1952 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, case, hearing
- Teachers Union File, re: Morris H. Lipschitz, 1952 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, hearing, appeal, appeal dismissal post cards, case, legal papers
- Teachers Union File, Local 555, miscellaneous, 1952-1953 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, announcement, exceptions to report. report, news clippings, memo, form letter, general release, bulletins, briefs, press release, post card
- Teachers Union File, re: Dorothy Rand, 1951-1952 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  Case, trial memo, summary, legal paper, statements, bulletins, form letter, correspondence, brief, interviews
- Teachers Union File, Supreme Court, Albany, Adler, Irvin and Wilson etc., et al, 1952-1953 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  Appeal, correspondence, cases, notes, press release, news clippings
- Teachers Union File, Vera Shlakman, et al vs. Board of Education, 1952-1954 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  Notices of Appeal, correspondence, resolution, news clippings releases
- Teachers Union File, Suspension of teachers, 1950 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  An act, subpoenas, record, correspondence, news clipping, opening statement, notice of pleading
- Teachers Union File, No. 1, Suspension of Teachers, Board of Education, proceedings, 1950-1951 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, news clippings, statement, release, notes, analysis, cases, resolution
- Teachers Union File, No. 2, Suspension of Teachers, 1950-1951 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, cases, appeals, photocopy, statement, news clippings, notes
- Teachers Union File, No. 4, Suspension of Teachers, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, cases, statement, memo, form letter
- Teachers Union File, re: Timone Resolution, 1950-1952 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, cases, resolution, speech, news clipping, statement, petition
- Teachers Union File, re: Use of school buildings for conduct of meetings, 1951-1953 (Box 86, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, news clippings, telegrams, appeals, brief, memo, statement, form letters
- Teachers Union File, re: Samuel Wallach et al, 1951-1952 (Box 86, Folder 6)
  Post card, correspondence, case, hearings, statement, appeals, appeal dismissal, legal papers
- Teachers Union File, witnesses, 1950 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  Legal papers, correspondence, notes
- Teachers Union Institute, in-service credit, 1939-1940 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, course registration
- Teachers Union Institute, 1940-1953 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  Bulletins, leaflets, play, radio script, minutes, reports, reference lists, registration schedule, correspondence, form letters, bibliography
- Teachers Union Local 555, miscellaneous matters, 1949-1952 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, cases, investigation, minutes, legal papers, releases
- Teachers Union, meeting, Carnegie Hall Bally, 1953 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  Press releases, program, bulletins, proof of advertisement, correspondence, form letter
- Teachers Union, membership meeting, 1950-1955 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, form letters, resolutions, press releases, bulletin
- Teachers Union, music teachers committee, 1950-1951 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, form letters, post cards
- Teachers Union, Organization Department, 1949-1952 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  Form letters, bulletins, notes
- Teachers Union, school chapters, 1950-1953 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, form letters, bulletins, report, post card; Teachers Union of Philadelphia See: Academic Freedom, Pennsylvania Loyalty Oath